pcrecruiter.net 2018-08-31

# Privacy Policy - PCRecruiter

## Main Sequence Technology Inc.

Privacy Policy

Effective Date: 10 November, 2017

Main Sequence Technology Inc. (“Main Sequence”), an Ohio corporation, provides this Privacy Statement to explain how we collect, use, and disclose certain personal information.

This statement discloses the privacy practices for [www.pcrecruiter.net](http://www.pcrecruiter.net/)  in **Section 1** and privacy practices for PCRecruiter accounts hosted by Main Sequence in **Section 2.**

## **Section 1**

[www.pcrecruiter.net](http://www.pcrecruiter.net/) is the corporate website of Main Sequence, a provider of online technology used by recruitment and hiring teams to post jobs, process applicants, and conduct recruitment operations worldwide. Direct hiring organizations, staffing companies, and search firms are Main Sequence’s primary customers. The website is primarily used for sales promotion and customers service of the company’s solutions.

We do not collect any personally identifiable information without user knowledge. Personally identifiable information is collected using forms. Personally identifiable information is optional for use of the website.  Specific types of information are collected as described below.

We collect non-personally identifiable information that may track browser type and monitor settings of a user. IP addresses are logged to track a user’s session. We do not link IP addresses to personally identifiable information. This means that a user’s session may be tracked, but the user will remain anonymous.

The website may optionally collect personally identifiable information such as name, company, and contact information. Our sales team uses this information to contact potential sales leads that may be interested in Main Sequence Solutions. This information is placed in our sales database.

All information sent using the careers section of our web site is placed directly into an applicant-tracking database for consideration by Main Sequence hiring authorities. All job applicant information will be held by Main Sequence as confidential.

All support information, such as logins and passwords to support systems, trouble tickets, and descriptions of issues are stored in databases. All support information is held by Main Sequence as confidential, and support information may additionally be subject to confidentiality provisions within account usage or software license agreements.

#### Security

The website and it’s associated databases are provisioned using commercially reasonable security measures to prevent the loss, misuse, or unauthorized alteration of the information under our control. Access to databases is restricted to qualified Main Sequence employees.

If you wish to change or update personally identifiable information, or if you are interested in removing information from Main Sequence database(s), please email: [webmaster@mainsequence.net](mailto:webmaster@mainsequence.net) or send your request via US postal mail to the address listed below.

Currently, Main Sequence does not share or sell any sales related information acquired through the [www.pcrecruiter.net](http://www.pcrecruiter.net/) website with any third parties.

In the event there is a change in Main Sequence’s corporate structure, including without limitation, merger, consolidation, sale, liquidation or transfer of substantial assets, Main Sequence may, in its sole and absolute discretion, transfer, sell or assign information collected, including without limitation aggregated information and personally identifiable information, to one or more affiliated or unaffiliated third parties.

## **Section** 2

pcrecruiter.net is the root URL used for hosted PCRecruiter accounts of Main Sequence customers. This privacy statement for pcrecruiter.net also applies to certain personal data that Main Sequence processes in the United States from the European Union.

PCRecruiter is used by our customers and third parties to facilitate hiring and recruitment activity. PCRecruiter maintains records of persons and documents associated with recruitment activity such as resumes/CV, recruiter notes, contact information, and in some instances third-party information such as background checks and job assessment reports.

**Privacy Statement for PCRecruiter Accounts**

Main Sequence is not responsible for the privacy and security practices of our customers. All information entered by customers (“Account Owners”) or third-parties at the direction or request of Account Owners at all times remain the sole property of the Account Owner. Main Sequence does not control or monitor the collection, use or disclosure of information collected from third-parties by Account Owners. Main Sequence is in the solutions hosting business, and from time to time may host databases for Account Owners at website addresses other than pcrecruiter.net.

By registering or authenticating to PCRecruiter, end-users allow PCRecruiter to identify them and give them access to services.

Third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In those instances, PCRecruiter will be able to access some data stored by third parties for registration or identification purposes.

Google OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by Google Inc. and is connected to the Google network. Information collected includes: openid – information about user accounts to verify identity, (not stored by Main Sequence), access to Google Calendar for synchronization (stored by Main Sequence), access to Google Contacts for synchronization (stored by Main Sequence)access to Google Tasks for synchronization (stored by Main Sequence) and access to email / notifications about errors or background tasks (stored by Main Sequence). Information about the referenced Google objects can be found here:

  * https://www.googleapis.com/auth/calendar
  * https://www.googleapis.com/auth/contacts
  * https://www.googleapis.com/auth/tasks
  * https://www.googleapis.com/auth/userinfo.email

All data stored by Main Sequence relating to these objects is considered PCRecruiter account information and subject to the contractual and privacy polices described elsewhere herein for PCRecruiter account information.

**Information for  EU Customers: **

The European Commission has established standards for the handling of personal information by information processors.   These standards exceed current US privacy standards.  Main Sequence offers contractual terms for EU customers that are compliant with these standards.  Those are known as “Model Contract Terms”.   In addition, Main Sequence participates in the US-EU negotiated Privacy Shield program.

Main Sequence complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States.  Main Sequence has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

Regardless of contractual or Privacy Shield status, the following privacy principles apply to the transfer, collection, use or disclosure by Main Sequence of personal information of third-parties (“Public Users”) and/or Account Owners from the EU:

**Notice:** Main Sequence informs Account Owners in the EU about the purposes for which it collects and uses their personal information, how to contact Main Sequence, the types of third parties with which Main Sequence shares their personal information, and the choice and means Main Sequence offers for limiting the use and disclosure of their personal information.

Main Sequence may not be in a position to furnish notice in certain situations. Specifically, notice is not required where the processing of EU personal information is necessary to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including national security or law enforcement requirements; or is necessary to protect Main Sequence’s legal interests and providing notice would interfere with those interests. Main Sequence provides copyright notices within its solutions to that Public Users may identify Main Sequence as the solution provider as a step toward contact with Account Owners. Main Sequence will make reasonable efforts to assure that Public Users can contact Account Owners when privacy concerns are presented.

the requirement for your organization to disclose personal information

**Choice:** Main Sequence will not process personal information about EU Account Owners for purposes other than those for which the information was originally obtained or subsequently authorized by the Account Owner unless the individual affirmatively and explicitly consents (“opt-in”) to the processing, or unless an exception applies.

Main Sequence also provides Account Owners with the opportunity to withdraw consent at any time (“opt-out”), in which case their personal information will not be further processed. The use of any opt-out provision by itself will not alter or abrogate any contractual obligations between the parties.

Main Sequence collects personal information that is adequate, relevant and not excessive for the purposes for which it is to be processed.

**Transfers To Third Parties:** Main Sequence will only transfer personal information about Account Owners or Public Users to third-parties where the third-party (a) has provided satisfactory assurances to Main Sequence that it will protect the information consistently with this Statement; or (b) is located in the EU or a country considered “adequate” for privacy by the EU Commission, and therefore is required to comply with the EU data protection laws or substantially equivalent privacy laws.

Where Main Sequence has knowledge that a third-party, including successor organizations, to whom it has provided EU personal information is processing that information in a manner contrary to this statement, Main Sequence will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the processing.

Upon written request to Main Sequence Main Sequence will provide EU Account Owners with an inventory of personal information held. Main Sequence will also take reasonable steps to allow Account Owners to review their information for the purposes of correcting their information.

Main Sequence does not disclose personal-information stored in PCRecruiter accounts to third-parties.

**Security:** Main Sequence takes commercially reasonable and appropriate precautions to protect EU personal information in its possession from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. Main Sequence will identify Account Owners if we make a determination that we can no longer meet our obligation to provide the level of protection required by the Privacy Shield principles.

**Enforcement:** Main Sequence has established internal mechanisms to verify its ongoing adherence to this Statement. Account Owners are parties to additional agreements with Main Sequence, which govern ownership and use of Information, dispute resolution, and other terms and conditions relating to the use of Main Sequence solutions.

Adherence to these Privacy Principles may be limited to the extent required to meet a legal, governmental, national security or public interest obligation.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Main Sequence commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Main Sequence at:

Main Sequence Technology Inc.  
Office of the President  
4420 Sherwin Road  
Hamilton Hall  
Willoughby, Ohio, USA 44094

1(440) 946-5214  
support@mainsequence.net

Privacy Shield assures broad rights of individuals to access personal information processed by Main Sequence, and Main Sequence may accrue liability in cases of onward transfers to third parties who do not comply with Privacy Shield principles.   Main Sequence is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).  Individuals may under certain conditions invoke binding arbitration.  In[ Annex I of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction) , the Department of Commerce committed to facilitating the establishment of a fund into which Privacy Shield organizations will be required to pay contributions to cover arbitral costs. The International Centre for Dispute Resolution-American Arbitration Association (ICDR-AAA) was selected to administer these arbitrations and manage this fund.  Main Sequence has paid our portion of these arbitral costs.

Main Sequence has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU.

**Main Sequence Privacy Statement for Australia:**

As of March 2014, important changes have been made to the Privacy Act of 1988.

The changes include a new set of Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) that will regulate the handling of personal information by Australian Government agencies and businesses with revenue greater than $3 million (AUS), those trading in personal information, and all private health service providers.

In pertinent part, these changes include:

**Personal information** is defined as ‘information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable:

•whether the information or opinion is true or not; and

•whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not’ (s 6(1)).

Common examples are an individual’s name, signature, address, telephone number, date of birth, medical records, bank account details, employment details and commentary or opinion about a person.

**Sensitive information** is defined as a subset of personal information including:

  * racial or ethnic origin
  * political opinions
  * membership of a political association
  * religious beliefs or affiliations
  * philosophical beliefs
  * membership of a professional or trade association
  * membership of a trade union
  * sexual orientation or practices, or
  * criminal record
  * health information about an individual
  * genetic information
  * biometric information that is to be used for the purpose of automated biometric verification or biometric identification, or
  * biometric templates.

In limited circumstances, providing personal information to a contractor to perform services on behalf of the APP entity may be a **use,** rather than a **disclosure.   **This occurs where the entity does not release the subsequent handling of personal information from its effective control. For example, if an entity provides personal information to a cloud service provider for the limited purpose of performing the services of storing and ensuring the entity may access the personal information, this may be a **‘use’** by the entity.

Main Sequence is not responsible beyond a) the elements defined herein and b) the written agreement between Main Sequence and each customer for the customer’s compliance with the Privacy Act.   All relevant disclosures, measures, methods, and limitations of the act beyond the provision of Cloud services, in compliance with the Privacy Act, are the entire responsibility of the customer.  At all times, any Personal or Sensitive Information supplied to Main Sequence Technology remains in the effective control of the account owner.  In order to qualify for this definition of “ **Use** “, the following circumstances will always apply to Australian customers of Main Sequence Technology:

  * A binding contract between the customer and Main Sequence will require Main Sequence to only handle the personal information for the limited purposes selected solely at the discretion of the customer.
  * The contract requires any subcontractors to agree to the same obligations, and
  * The contract gives the entity effective control of how the information is handled by the provider, including the following:
  * The customer retains the right or power to access, change or retrieve the information*
  * The security measures taken by Main Sequence will be representative of similar measures taken by similar vendors of similar services at similar times.
  * The information can be retrieved or permanently deleted by the customer when no longer required, or at the end of the contract.*In the event a customer account is intact, but suspended for non-payment or other mechanism of default, and the customer requests the ability to engage in activity related to compliance with the Privacy Act,  Main Sequence will a) make commercially reasonable efforts to accommodate the request or b) immediately terminate the account and return all **personal information** to the account owner.  The final and complete destruction of personal account information will proceed with the general account data archive policies in effect at Main Sequence at the time of account termination.  All pertinent compliance requirements will remain binding on Main Sequence until such final destruction of account data.

**Contact information for Main Sequence:**

Main Sequence Technology Inc.  
4420 Sherwin Road  
Willoughby, OH 44094  
(440) 946 –5214
